Chapter 3: A Discussion and a Request

After Rio met up with Celia and Aishia, Liselotte led the three of them to a guest suite inside the mansion.

The guest suite consisted of a spacious living room, three bedrooms, and even a small kitchen and bathroom — making it a little more extravagant than the suite at the inn they stayed at. She also offered to assign them their own personal attendant, but they immediately turned down the offer politely.

At present, Rio was preparing tea while the two girls gathered at the living room sofa. Once Rio was seated, he looked at Aishia and Celia. “Now, I’d like to confirm what information the two of you have and exchange some of my own. If there’s anything you’d like to report or anything you’re curious about, please make sure you speak up.”

“Okay. But that’s easier said than done. I don’t even know where to start. It was all such a disaster,” Celia nodded with a slightly unwell expression. Having witnessed the damage first-hand, she must have been worried about those from the Beltrum Kingdom.

Rio sensed what Celia was feeling turmoil over and took the initiative to broach the subject. “...Then, there’s one thing I’d like to report first.”

“What is it?” Celia asked. Aishia listened silently.

“It is most likely... No, almost certain that my identity has been revealed to Princess Flora,” Rio confessed uncomfortably.

Celia looked shocked. “...Huh?”

“Princess Flora has an idea of who I am, with almost certain accuracy,” Rio repeated, as his words were of the utmost importance.

Naturally, Celia was panicked. “W-Why?! Is that okay?”

“I can’t be sure, but it’s fine... I think. Unless my judgment was wrong and Princess Flora has the type of personality to spread rumors everywhere, that is,” Rio replied in near self-mockery. Celia, however, was awfully confused and thought an explanation was in order.

“W-Wait! Hold it! Why was it revealed in the first place?”

“The kidnapper that had history with me said my name in front of Princess Flora. He didn’t give enough information to completely declare it was me, but it seems like Princess Flora is strongly convinced of her own judgment...” Rio explained with a bitter smile.

“Did you confess to her? That you’re Rio?” Celia asked fearfully. She was curious about the man Rio had a past with too, but Flora was more important right now.

“No. I made a vague comment to go along with her, then explained it as being two different people.”

“W-What does that mean, exactly?”

“I accepted the fact I had another name — Rio — then informed her that my name was now Haruto and asked her to forget that Rio is another name of mine.”

“...What did Princess Flora say to that?”

“...She apologized and accepted it as her misunderstanding, while crying,” Rio replied with difficulty.

“I... see... Okay.” Celia looked terribly frustrated, but accepted that answer nonetheless.

Rio frowned at the resurfacing memory of Flora’s crying face. “...Do you think it would be dangerous to believe in Princess Flora?”

“No. Princess Flora wouldn’t spread that needlessly. That’s what I believe,” Celia offered with a fleeting smile. She had spoken to Flora numerous times herself on a personal basis, so she knew fairly well that she didn’t have that kind of personality. Not to mention that she felt extremely guilty about what had happened to Rio...

For a moment, Celia hesitated over whether to tell Rio what Flora felt, but nothing would change in the short-term even if she did. Imagining how her former student must have felt hurt Celia’s heart, but she didn’t want to give Rio unnecessary knowledge to make him worry more right now.

For some strange reason, I felt happy when I saw Rio talking to Princess Flora and Roanna... I’m no good, honestly. Celia sighed deeply. It was extremely difficult to repair a relationship that had warped to that extent.

“...And there’s also another thing I’m late to report on, but I’ve been able to identify one of the heroes I was searching for,” Rio said after a brief pause.

“Oh, really?” Celia said in surprise.

“Yes. I heard it yesterday, when I was having a meal with Liselotte and Duke Huguenot. I’m assisting a little more in the investigations for the incident this time, but once that’s done I’m thinking of visiting Miharu... The people that were summoned from another world. It may be dangerous to remain in this city, too.”

“I see...”

“By the way, it should take about two to three weeks for me to go to Miharu and back.”

Celia nodded. “Got it.”

“In that time, I think you and Aishia should wait somewhere. I know it hasn’t been long since you fled the Kingdom of Beltrum, so I’m very sorry for making you go through this... Aishia, you too. Sorry,” Rio said regretfully.

“Don’t worry about it. There are some things I want to think about too.” Celia gave a fleeting smile and shook her head.

“I’m fine too. Leave it to me.” Aishia gave an earnest nod.

“Thank you.” Rio smiled at Aishia, before looking closely at Celia. “That’s all from me, but do you have any questions?”

“...Umm,” Celia opened her mouth quietly after a pause.

“Yes, what is it?”

“What happened between you and that man who abducted Princess Flora? You said you had a past...” Celia asked Rio hesitantly, watching his expression.

“...” Rio made a troubled face, wondering what to reply with.

“Ah, of course, if you don’t want to say then you don’t have to tell me anything, okay? I was just a little curious, that’s all,” Celia said in a fluster.

Rio steadied his resolve and responded calmly. “No, it’s just that the past we have isn’t exactly a fun story to listen to. Do you still want to hear it? If the Professor wants to hear it, then I’ll tell you.”

“...Yeah,” Celia nodded slowly.

“Okay,” Rio assented. “Lucius is the target of my revenge. Before I became an orphan in Beltrum, I had my mother killed right before my eyes by this man, and it is possible my father met a similar fate by him too.” He tried to state the truth as flatly as possible.

Celia paled with a gasp. “I-I’m sorry! For asking about something so painful...” She had expected a certain degree of tragedy from Rio’s behavior, but the truth was so shocking she reflexively apologized.

“No, I wish there was a better way of telling you, but I had always intended on telling you the truth if you asked, Professor. Don’t worry about it,” Rio laughed uncomfortably.

“R-Really?” Celia peered at Rio’s face.

“Yes. Once you had found out a glimpse of the relationship between Lucius and I, it’d only be natural to feel curious, and I didn’t want to lie to you if at all possible,” Rio said, the smile at his lips a little sad.

“I... I see. Did you know about this, Aishia?” Celia’s voice squeaked in shock as she looked at Aishia.

“I knew,” Aishia confirmed in a flat tone.

“I see...” Celia seemed a little relieved at that, sighing quietly in acceptance.

“If possible, I hope you can keep what I have just said between just the three of us,” Rio said. Not even Miharu nor Sara and the others knew. It wasn’t a topic one would want spread around.

Celia paused for a brief moment, then nodded deeply. “...Yeah, I got it. But can I ask one more thing?”

“Yes?”

“Do you hate him, Rio?”

“...I don’t think I could forgive him, but my emotions are a little different from hatred or disgust. I can’t explain it all that well,” Rio contemplated with a slightly troubled look. His feelings were no longer definable on a scale of hatred or disgust anymore. The notion of killing Lucius had become a fixed concept within Rio’s mind. He saw nothing but his goal of killing. That was his resolute decision.

“What does...?” Celia cocked her head dubiously.

“I can’t forgive him, but constantly cursing him would grow tiring. It may sound contradictory, but my feelings are much more indifferent than that. It’s just that I’ve already reached an answer within myself, like I’ve decided to face this without running... I cannot explain it with logic,” Rio said, smiling as though he was over it. Celia watched Rio’s confident nature, but still cocked her head dubiously.

“Okay... I see. Fine, then. Thank you for telling me.” Celia smiled gently and nodded.

Of course, it wasn’t because she had completely understood Rio and agreed with him. As someone who had never been in a similar environment, there was no way for Celia to see through the particulars of Rio’s feelings in the first place.

However, Celia knew Rio. She knew what kind of person he was, which was why she could trust him. While she wasn’t without worries or anxieties, she trusted Rio unconditionally and believed that that was the way to respect someone.

Rio looked awkward, but still relaxed his mouth into a smile. “I should be the one saying that. Thank you very much.”

“Not at all. You can come to me anytime if you want to talk about anything, you know?” Celia peered at Rio’s face.

“Yes. The same goes for you, Professor. About your future,” Rio nodded and said in return.

“...Yup. I’ll spend some time thinking about it.” Celia also looked a little awkward as she nodded bashfully.

◇　◇　◇

Afterwards, Rio and the girls spent some time in the room relaxing after the tense encounters that had taken place that day. They drank tea together, took a nap, had a meal, and before they knew it, it was nighttime.

It was at that time that Natalie, the attendant, visited the guest suite they were staying at.

“Sir Haruto, I apologize for disturbing you after your dinner, but would you have a moment? My master wishes to speak with you,” Natalie said.

“Understood,” Rio replied immediately, and headed towards Liselotte. Celia and Aishia remained in the guest suite.

“Lady Liselotte, Sir Haruto has arrived,” Natalie announced with a knock after leading Rio to the meeting room.

“Come in,” Liselotte’s reply came immediately.

“After you, Sir Haruto.” Natalie opened the door and gestured for Rio to go inside.

“If you would excuse me,” Rio gave a single bow and entered the room. Other than Liselotte, Duke Huguenot, Flora, Hiroaki, and Roanna were also in the room. Furthermore, Aria was also present. As soon as Rio appeared, Flora reacted by shaking her body with a flinch.

“Thank you for coming, Sir Haruto. I apologize for summoning you so late,” Liselotte said in welcome. She must have been exhausted at this point, as she didn’t look all that well.

“It’s no problem at all.” Rio shook his head in a friendly manner.

Liselotte gestured for Rio to take a seat. “Please.” And so, Rio took a seat at the round table set up in the meeting room.

“We really have been greatly indebted to you, Haruto. I’m not sure how we could ever repay you enough,” Duke Huguenot said with a somewhat apologetic laugh, already seated at the table.

Rio shook his head with a faint smile. “There is no need for that. How are your injuries?”

“All well, thanks to you. It appears I will have no hindrance to my daily life.”

“That’s good to hear.”

“This may be repetitive, but we truly want to thank you from the bottom of our hearts. Considerations for your reward are underway, but first let us discuss the incident in detail.”

When Duke Huguenot indicated his intention to give a reward, Rio paused for a faint moment before assenting. “...Understood.” Thus, the topic promptly shifted to discussion of the incident.

“Umm, Sir Haruto,” Flora said.

“What is it?” Rio responded without delay.

“Thank you very much, with regards to what transpired,” Flora said, bowing her head deeply to Rio.

“I’d like to extend you my gratitude once more too. Thank you very much for saving Princess Flora.” Roanna immediately bowed her head to Rio as well.

“It was no problem at all.” Rio didn’t seem to want the conversation to drag out, as he omitted any unnecessary preamble and briefly shook his head.

Meanwhile, Hiroaki had remained silent the entire time up until this point. “...It seems you were sure busy this time.”

“Are you in better health now too, hero? I had heard that you fell unconscious after releasing your power...” Rio asked while examining Hiroaki’s face.

“Who knows. You say that, but all I did was exterminate a couple of those cockroach-like monsters before spending the rest of the time sleeping. The one who had the biggest spotlight defeating minotaurs and rescuing Flora was you, wasn’t it?” Hiroaki said in a blunt, sulking tone. His words almost sounded like he was jealous of Rio’s achievements.

...What’s that about? Rio couldn’t understand why Hiroaki was in a bad mood, so he tread carefully.

“I highly doubt that to be the case...”

“No no, your stocks are only soaring higher. There are rumors about you circulating everywhere in the mansion. It’s almost like the birth of a new hero. Right, Flora?” Hiroaki said, suddenly addressing the princess.

“Eh? Ah, y-yes.” Surprised, Flora nodded along on the spur of the moment.

“See? Told you.” Hiroaki shrugged his shoulders, unimpressed.

“Sir Haruto, your tea.” Aria approached Rio and quietly placed tea on the table. Beneath the teacup was a piece of paper with writing on it.

Rio narrowed his eyes when he spotted the letter under the cup. He wondered if it was Aria’s writing; it was written in excellent penmanship. After witnessing the attendants praising your contributions, combined with the fact his own efforts fell short, he has been left in a bit of a sulky mood. The fact that Princess Flora has taken an interest in you has also been another source of his bad mood. We apologize for the trouble.

There was no need for Aria to be the one apologizing at all. It was more likely that Hiroaki had been the one to demand his presence at their meeting, and there was no way for anyone to deny him.

I see. Rio understood what Hiroaki must be feeling and thanked Aria courteously. Meanwhile —

Bah, what is this? This dull, dull feeling... Like having a newbie join and receive clear favoritism from their superiors right away. Nothing kills the mood more than this... Hiroaki’s eyes must have been clouded with envy, as his thoughts were completely unreasonable.

It was true that giving preferential treatment to a newbie with no achievements whatsoever could only be interpreted as favoritism. It was an action that would antagonize the senior figures that had supported the organization until now, in some way or another.

However, it was a different story when that newbie had already shown more outstanding results than the senior figures, objectively proving their worth and capability. Any good organization would give such talented figures a befitting amount of appreciation.

If anything, it would be a problem if an incompetent person was valued more highly than a talented person. Organizations were not formed from machines, after all. If incompetence was praised and talent ignored, the talented people would naturally feel discontent. There were plenty of other opportunities to be had by talented people, so only the incompetent ones would inevitably remain in the organization.

Of course, there were some cases of organizations placing higher value on areas other than visible results, but he wasn’t a psychic. There was no way he could see through that; he wouldn’t know unless it was indicated as such. Not to mention that Rio was a person outside of the organization. For Liselotte and Duke Huguenot, he was their savior and the largest contributor to the relief efforts, making him someone they wanted to get closer to by all means. He had achieved results that were objectively impossible to fault, so it was only natural for him to be praised. Or rather, they would be distancing themselves from Rio if they didn’t, which would make Liselotte lose face.

That was why Hiroaki’s discontent towards the warm hospitality being shown to Rio was simply being misdirected. Or rather, if he was envious, then he should have used that envy as a driving force instead. But Hiroaki lacked the spirit for that.

Ah yes, the neutral side character that appears later than the main character while being stronger too. The one that has to ruin the overpowered uniqueness of the main character, right? What a drag.

Hiroaki disapproved of Rio from whatever point of view he could think of. In his head, he was being logical, but the fact his evaluation was based off his emotions meant it was anything but.

“Hah,” Hiroaki sighed dramatically.

Liselotte watched him with a somewhat fed up look in her eyes. She was the one who wanted to sigh, after all. Even Duke Huguenot was frowning a little, ill at ease.

Roanna’s face was slightly panicked, having realized the situation wasn’t good. Flora’s entire attention was focused on Rio, so she didn’t have any room left to care about Hiroaki right now.

However, Hiroaki’s value as a hero was far too great to just ignore. It would be a problem to have him sulk forever over such a trivial matter, not to mention annoying.

I believe it would be best to proceed with the discussions.

Agreed.

Liselotte and Duke Huguenot reached a mutual understanding with an exchange of eye contact. They had already settled what topics to discuss in advance, so their plans were already laid out.

They actually wanted to use this chance to discuss the reward too, but it would have to wait for another time when Hiroaki wasn’t present. “Now that Haruto is here, let us get straight into the main topic at hand. What I wish to discuss with you is about the mercenary, Lucius. I know some things about that man’s background,” Duke Huguenot said.

“...Is that so?” Rio gazed in wonder at the unexpected source of information about Lucius.

“I have heard that you have a certain past with this Lucius man. There may be information useful to you among this.”

“I am most grateful.” Rio bowed once and waited for the conversation to continue.

“I do not know where Lucius conducts his activities now, but he was originally from a lower class noble family in our kingdom. His family name was Orgueil. The house fell a long time ago, though,” Duke Huguenot explained.

“Haruto, were you...”

“I was unaware.” Rio shook his head slowly.

“Which means you only know of Lucius as a mercenary, then. It is most likely that you met him after his family had fallen out of grace, then. On the other hand, I only know of what he was like before that...” Duke Huguenot said, examining Rio closely.

“...I only knew him for a brief period of time, when I was a child. I do not have any direct knowledge of what he was doing as a mercenary.”

“I see... Then let me fill you in a little on what he was like when he was a noble. Lucius Orgueil was a former candidate for the position of the King’s Sword, competing neck and neck with the current King’s Sword, Sir Alfred Emarle,” Duke Huguenot explained.

“That means his ability as a swordsman was fairly high, then,” Liselotte confirmed.

“Yes. If I recall correctly, there were some who believed that he would have been selected as the King’s Sword if his family status had been more favorable. I personally didn’t find Sir Alfred’s abilities lacking in any way, but our kingdom values more aspects than just ability,” Duke Huguenot said, huffing in a self-mocking sneer. His gaze was directed at Aria, who was formerly a lower class noble of Beltrum. Aria received Duke Huguenot’s gaze with her usual unconcerned look.

“The reason why Lucius wasn’t selected as the King’s Sword was because his family fell before the selection. It wouldn’t be an overstatement to say that the fate of the Orgueil house rested on Lucius’ shoulders at the time, but the house reached its limit before anything could happen. Although, there are rumors suspecting that their ruin was directly caused by certain circumstances where exterior pressure was being exerted. Well... Who knows what the truth is,” Duke Huguenot added in his eloquent way of speaking.

“...What kind of path do nobles that lose their house normally pursue?” Rio asked.

“Falling into ruin is an extreme disgrace for a noble. Not all doors are closed to them afterwards, but their lives have basically ceased to exist. There are many cases where the whole house commits suicide or are never seen again. Of course, there are those among them like Aria, who distinguish themselves instead. Lucius belongs to that select group,” Duke Huguenot explained.

“Considering the incident this time, it may be possible that this Lucius man holds a strong grudge towards Beltrum Kingdom,” Liselotte said, offering a hypothesis.

“You think that may be the motive behind Princess Flora’s abduction?” asked Rio.

“Yes. Of course, there may be a motive beyond personal reasons, but I’d like to hear what Sir Haruto thinks after actually fighting this Lucius,” Liselotte said, seeking Rio’s opinion.

“...I’m not sure. However, I believe he prioritized his own pleasure when it came to the fight with me — someone he was connected to — over the abduction of Princess Flora.” Rio offered his impressions as he looked back on the series of events up to their fight.

“What kind of a person did this Lucius seem like to you, Sir Haruto?” Liselotte looked at Rio and asked.

“He was a monster in a human skin. Cunning and calculative, he seems to move in a logical manner, but actually takes illogical actions in pursuit of his own pleasure. A savage and devious man,” Rio stated bluntly.

“If you think that of him, then...” Liselotte’s eyes widened faintly. From what she had heard so far, he seemed like a terrible person. Even though he didn’t seem like the type to openly speak ill of others, Rio had gone out of his way to say just that, so he must have a particularly deep connection with Lucius. This meant that in order to support this personal criticism, there was a need to know how Rio and Lucius were related, but the topic was rather delicate and made it difficult to ask. If it was just a matter of asking and being refused, then it would be fine, but she wanted to avoid upsetting him. That being said, as reluctant as she was, she had no other choice but to ask right now. She’d just have to prepare herself for the worst.

With that thought, Liselotte opened her mouth, when —

“Excuse me. I apologize if this is an intrusive question, but may I inquire as to what kind of connection Sir Haruto has with this man called Lucius?” Roanna, who had been listening silently until now, suddenly asked. Perhaps she had read the mood in the air and realized it would be safer for her to ask than Liselotte or Duke Huguenot, who were in positions of negotiation that could potentially occur in the future.

Rio kept an uncomfortable smile on his face as he answered. “...My mother was killed before my very eyes.”

It wasn’t a past he wanted to tell people, but he couldn’t refuse to answer considering the situation they were in. However, the past that he revealed was so tragic, Roanna turned white as a ghost and apologized in a panic. “...I-I am so very sorry.”

“No, there’s nothing to apologize for,” Rio replied immediately.

“Ah... Well, like Liselotte said, if he’s doing this out of resentment for the Kingdom of Beltrum, then he must be quite the petty man.” Even Hiroaki felt pity for the awkward question Roanna had asked and tried to change the topic.

A-Are you one to talk, acting all jealous over Sir Haruto mere moments ago? Liselotte thought tiredly, but didn’t say anything out loud. Humans were terrible at objectively looking at themselves, after all. Anyway, if Hiroaki hadn’t supported Roanna there, Liselotte would have spoken up herself.

Chapter 5: Departure

The next morning, after Rio, Latifa, Miharu’s group, and Sara’s group finished breakfast, they all paid a visit to the town hall and applied for a meeting with the head elders. Shortly after, they were led to a room inside the town hall.

“Welcome. Please, take a seat,” Syldora said warmly.

“Thank you very much. Miharu — you, Aki, and Masato can sit there,” Rio said, urging the three of them into the seats opposite the head elders. Latifa, Sara, Orphia, and Alma took the seats to the side.

“Excuse me.” Miharu politely bowed before sitting down. Rio took the seat next to her and faced the head elders.

“You reached a conclusion faster than we expected,” Ursula the werefox said.

“Yes — The three of them discussed it. Last night, Sara and the girls joined in, and I listened too. I would like to respect the decision that they made,” Rio replied smoothly.

Syldora looked at the three of them and nodded. “I see. Then let us hear what you have decided at once. Lord Rio, if you please.”

Rio nodded, getting straight to the point by reporting the conclusion of their conversation. “Yes. To start, the three of them want to head to Strahl.”

“I see.” The elders nodded solemnly. They had predicted this, but it was one of two options: remain in the village, or leave for the Strahl region. It was a matter of whether they all chose the same option or each took on a different option, but it was all within their expectations.

“In regards to what happens after moving to Strahl, Aki and Masato will wait nearby the castle. Miharu wants to attend the banquet with me, so I plan on consulting with the noble that has invited me to see if Miharu can attend too.”

“I understand. That sounds acceptable,” Syldora said in a stately manner.

Suddenly, Miharu stood up with great force. “Umm, everyone in the village has been so terribly nice to us even though our circumstances were forced upon you, and now we’re leaving at our own convenience, so I’m truly sorry for everything!” Miharu must have been nervous, as her voice was high pitched as she bowed her head in deep regret.

“There’s no need to be so anxious, Lady Miharu. You’ve finally obtained a clue towards your friend and family. There’s no need to deny your feelings of wanting to meet them.” Syldora gave a good-natured smile as he spoke to Miharu.

Ursula agreed cheerfully. “Indeed. It’ll be a little lonely around here, but it’s your future. You need to find clues on how to return to your world. There’s no need to let it bother you.”

Dominic raised both hands to support their decision. “Well, if you run into any danger, you can just return to the village. Like Rio, you young ones are already like our brethren too.”

Ursula nodded with a smile. “That’s right. If you ever feel like you’re in danger, you can return to the village.”

“T-Thank you very much!” Miharu bit her lip, moved by her emotions, and bowed her head deeply once more. Aki and Masato followed her, and with their thanks, bowed their heads too.

“Raise your heads, the three of you,” Syldora said with a troubled look as Ursula looked at Rio.

“By the way, Lord Rio. How do you intend on getting to Strahl?”

“I plan on carrying them by air, of course,” he replied. While there was a teleportation crystal to the village, there wasn’t one back to the Strahl region, which meant the only two options were to walk or fly.

“By yourself, Lord Rio?” Ursula confirmed carefully.

“...Yes,” Rio said with a little hesitation.

“Well, it’s true that Lord Rio may be able to pull that off...” Ursula said, looking at Syldora and Dominic. Then, she turned to look at Sara, Orphia, and Alma.

“Uh...” They looked like they wanted to say something, but when the head elders directed their attention on them they flinched. The head elders smirked, nodding at each other with smiles at their lips.

“In that case, you should take Sara, Orphia, and Alma along,” Syldora said.

“...Huh? No, but...” Rio gazed in wonder, but shook his head at the same time. He had the faint suspicion they would offer to help from the moment Ursula brought up his method of travel, but he hadn’t expected this.

“It’s fine. Those three probably intended as much in the first place,” Ursula said, suddenly turning to Sara and the others.

“Eh... ah. Umm, yes. I never imagined it’d be so easy, and suggested by the head elders themselves...” Sara flinched and said fearfully.

“...” Rio couldn’t find the words to say, frowning apologetically.

“That’s that. It’s decided,” Dominic summarized with a smug huff.

“But what about the village’s laws? The residents of the village can’t wander into the outside world recklessly.” Rio tried to put a stop to things through his confusion. Because of this law, neither the spirit folk girls nor Rio himself could make the final call on accompanying him.

“The law is to forbid anyone from leaving without the approval of the three head elders or the majority of the council. As for the approval of the three head elders, well, here you go,” Ursula said with a joyful laugh.

“Uh...” Rio uttered, completely losing track of his thoughts.

It was certainly something he was grateful for — however, he felt a deep sense of regret over the fact that their harsh exceptions for their law were being disregarded for him so easily.

“Umm, it pains us to see you go through so much trouble for us, and we’re already forcing Haruto to take on so much... I don’t know...” Miharu said in a fluster. She felt bad leaving everything to Rio, but that didn’t mean it didn’t hurt to cause trouble for the village too. She was certainly stuck between a rock and a hard place.

“Look, now Lady Miharu is troubled, and her firm resolution may end up wavering. It’s a bad habit of Lord Rio’s to act too considerately,” Ursula said with a grin at Miharu.

Rio gave an awkward and strained smile before looking at the head elders and the spirit folk girls and bowing his head. “...That is most shameful of me. Then, I shall take you up on your offer. Can I ask that of you?”

“Of course!” Sara, Orphia, and Alma agreed enthusiastically.

“Also. For these youngsters who will one day lead the village, we normally order them to leave on a journey to the human realms to widen their views. Of course, we give them magic artifacts that change their appearance to that of a human’s.” So don’t worry about it, was what Dominic was saying.

“While it still feels a little early for that... If Lord Rio is with them, then we don’t need to worry. That’s why it’s a two way exchange,” Ursula said, laughing.

“The three of you should learn about the outside world while acting as escorts for Lady Miharu. It will be a good learning experience,” Syldora said, looking at the girls as he spoke words of encouragement.

“Yes sir!” They agreed enthusiastically.

“W-Wait!” Latifa yelled. She had been watching the conversation with a dazed look until now; a sudden look of panic was on her face.

Rio could tell what Latifa was thinking and called her name with a troubled look. “Latifa...”

“W-What about me?” Latifa asked worriedly.

“...Latifa, you stay back at the village,” Rio said to her in warning.

“N-No! If Sara and the others are going, I’m going too!” Latifa objected in shock.

“You can’t.” Rio shook his head bluntly.

“Why not?!” Latifa questioned with tears in her eyes.

“...You have bad memories of the Strahl region, do you not?” Rio asked with difficulty.

“Yes, but...!” Latifa’s face contorted as she clenched her fists.

“You’ve been waiting at the village all this time, remember? It’s not like we’re going to play,” Rio scratched his neck, trying to admonish Latifa.

“This is different than before! Miharu’s group is going, Sara and the others are going, Aishia is waiting over there... I don’t want to be the only one left behind! Take me with you this time! Just this time!” Latifa pleaded desperately.

Latifa... Miharu watched Latifa in frustration.

Yesterday, after talking to Latifa alone, Miharu had found out just how much Latifa loved Rio. She understood why Latifa was so desperate more than anyone else present. She didn’t want to be left behind by Haruto — Miharu decided to attend the banquet and hold her own future in her hands because of that, so she could relate.

“Umm, I know I’m not in the position to ask for anything, but can’t Latifa come along too?” Miharu could no longer sit still and pleaded Rio and the head elders.

“Not you too, Miharu...” Rio was completely at a loss.

“Hmm, I don’t think we should reject her accompanying you without listening to her first,” Ursula, who was also Latifa’s guardian, suddenly said.

“...May I ask why?” Rio asked Ursula with a small sigh.

“Three years ago, when you told Latifa you were leaving for the Yagumo region, Latifa did not ask to go along with you, though she did ask you not to go. Is that right?” Ursula confirmed with Rio.

“Yes.” Rio nodded uncomfortably.

“Back then, she was still unconsciously afraid of going outside. That’s probably why Latifa herself didn’t think of leaving the village. But this time, she’s requesting to go outside of her own volition. If so, this could be a good opportunity for her to grow in order to erase her past scars.” Ursula looked back on the past emotionally as she spoke of the benefits of Latifa heading to the Strahl region.

“...” Rio didn’t want to dismiss Latifa’s feelings and ignore an opportunity for her to grow either. However, he was still worried as her older brother, fearing her trauma would resurface.

“I want to go with Onii-chan. I want to stay by your side.” Latifa slowly stood up, approaching Rio and fearfully grabbing his sleeve.

As everyone in the room focused their attention on them, Rio hesitated for a long moment before speaking up. “...I have conditions.”

“W-What?!” Latifa’s face brightened immediately.

“...Even if we go there, you won’t be able to stay with me constantly. Miharu and I have to attend the banquet, so you absolutely have to listen to the words of Aishia, or Sara, or Professor Celia, who will be with us there.”

“Okay!”

“You can’t whine at them and cause trouble. You must refrain from acting selfishly. If you want to go anywhere, you cannot go alone — you get absorbed in things too quickly. Also...”

“Fu...” A giggle could be heard in the room.

“...Is something the matter?” Rio looked around at the people in the room curiously. The head elders, spirit folk girls, and humans were all smiling in amusement.

“Nothing, we were just thinking that you’re rather overprotective,” Ursula said.

“...I still have another condition. Unless you get proper permission from Elder Syldora and Dominic too, you can’t come along. It’s the village’s law.” Rio sighed tiredly.

“I don’t mind,” said Dominic.

“Me neither,” Syldora answered immediately.

“...I would have appreciated a little more than just that,” Rio said, candidly expressing his bewilderment.

“The reason is as Ursula said. What more do you want us to say? You’ve covered all the warnings yourself. That’s why I choose not to say anything. That’s all.” Dominic smiled faintly and shrugged his shoulders.

“If I had to say, then Latifa’s development has been a bit of a special case. We’ve considered those circumstances too. In regards to the concerns, my judgment is that it is not a problem if Lord Rio is there,” Syldora said.

“...Yeah, if I could add one thing. If you need a new lodging to stay in while on the move, I can prepare an extra stone house. After we made the previous one for you, we found it so fun that we made a couple more. This would be one of those. They’re extra anyway, so take it with you,” Dominic offered generously.

“Oh? In that case, you can depart immediately. When will you go?” Ursula was completely in favor of that and pushed the conversation forward.

“...There’s still time before the banquet, but I wouldn’t want to be late because of issues while moving. I think the earlier the better,” Rio replied, giving up.

“At the latest, a few days, and at the earliest, the day after tomorrow? Which means...”

Ursula placed a hand against her mouth and hummed in thought.

“We need to throw a party for everyone’s departure!” Dryas manifested in a corner of the room. The sudden appearance of the high rank spirit left everyone wide eyed in shock.

“...Lady Dryas, were you listening?” Ursula asked, sighing in exasperation.

“Yes, but just the end. It didn’t seem like the right mood to interrupt, so I was being considerate,” Dryas replied in a pleasant mood. She truly was whimsical and elusive.

“No wonder Ariel stirred within me for a moment.”

“Hel too...”

“Ifritah as well.”

Sara and Alma had also sensed the change in their contract spirits. Spirits could sense other spirits’ presences, so they had probably noticed Dryas approaching in her spirit form.

“Heh, I was hiding my aura pretty seriously too... You kids have grown as well,” Dryas praised, impressed by the contract spirits residing within the spirit folk girls. “By the way, is Aishia not here this time? She hasn’t suddenly learned how to completely hide her aura... right?” she asked, looking around the room.

“Yes, this time she’s waiting back at the Strahl region,” Rio answered with a smile.

“I see. Well, I’ve heard the general gist of things and we can discuss the details later, but for now, it’s time to celebrate everyone’s departure with a party! Let’s get ready!” Dryas suggested triumphantly.

“Understood. How about tomorrow night? We can use the food hall in the town hall where we held the party when they first arrived too. If villagers are going to the outside world, various people need to be informed too.” Ursula seemed to have intended on doing that to begin with, as she wrapped up the talk immediately.

“Sara, Orphia, Alma,” Syldora called out.

“Yes,” the spirit folk girls replied, bracing themselves.

“Go back to your parents’ homes tonight. Other than your own will and our permission, you need the agreement from your blood relatives too. Inform your families with your own words — that you have been handed a duty.”

“Yes!” At Syldora’s order, the three of them agreed enthusiastically. Thus, it was decided that the party to celebrate their departure would be held tomorrow night.

◇　◇　◇

The next night, everyone gathered in the dining room at the lowest floor of the town hall. All the upper echelons of the village and their families were gathered and chatting pleasantly. The tables around the room were crammed with food and drinks prepared to celebrate their departure.

“Miharu! I wanted to learn more recipes from you, and talk to you about so much more! It’s going to be lonely. I’m so sad,” the werecat Anya lamented as she clung to Miharu.

At present, Miharu was surrounded by Anya and the young women of the village who were sadly saying their farewells. They were all students of the cooking classroom that Miharu held.

“I wanted to talk to you guys more too,” Miharu replied with a sad smile.

“Hmph, okay! We can have a long talk just between us girls! Nothing gloomy allowed! We’ll have lots of fun with girl talk!” Anya said with enthusiasm, squeezing Miharu tightly. The girls around them were all on board too, making an excited fuss.

Meanwhile, elsewhere in the room, Vera was also grieving over saying farewell to Latifa and Aki. “Ugh, sudden farewells are so sad! I can’t believe Latifa is going too!” Her eyes were filled with tears as she hugged the two of them.

“Ahaha, that hurts, Vera.” Despite saying that, Latifa didn’t actually resist, just standing there being hugged with a quiet expression.

“...Sorry. It was decided suddenly,” Aki said apologetically.

“Aww... you leave tomorrow, right? When will we meet again?” Vera asked, clinging to Aki and Latifa.

“...I don’t know. But I want to see Vera again. If I can come back, then I want to. You’re my precious friend, after all,” Aki explained, expressing thoughts that were separate from her feelings of wanting to see her brother and Satsuki and return home.

“It’s a promise! If you don’t come, I’ll cry!” Vera said, sniffling as she hugged the two of them even tighter.

“Yup...” Aki and Latifa nodded solemnly.

“Geez, you’re all exaggerating so much,” Arslan said tiredly. He and Masato had been watching the exchange silently beside them the entire time.

“Haha, right,” Masato agreed with a strained smile.

“You say that, but aren’t the two of you going to say goodbye?! Latifa aside, we don’t know if Aki and Masato will be able to come back.” Vera puffed her cheeks up indignantly, glaring at them with a reproachful look.

“No... Well, doing that between men is a bit, you know. A bit shameful, or weak looking? It makes me itchy,” Arslan said, scratching his neck.

“That’s right. Anyway, I intend on coming back. I still haven’t won against him once yet, after all,” Masato said, glancing at Arslan, who stood beside him.

“Ha, as if. I’m going to get even stronger. I won’t lose next time we meet, either,” Arslan snorted smugly.

“Well, you just wait. Until I get stronger, that is.”

“Ha, I guess I can wait, though I’m not expecting anything. ...Just be careful on your trip.”

“Yeah.”

They both reached for a fist bump. Vera stared closely at the exchange between the two boys. “What’s with that? After saying those wannabe cool things, you’re being so much more embarrassing than both of us,” she said bluntly with a cold gaze.

“Oh, I thought that too!”

“Me too!”

Latifa and Aki immediately agreed.

“Geez, you could be a little more honest.” Aki grinned, looking at Masato and Arslan.

“Right?”

“Right.”

Latifa and Vera nodded while giggling.

“H-Huh?! That’s not true!” Masato and Arslan both objected with red faces.

“Aww, but it’s true. Right, you two?” Vera rebutted with a huff of laughter, then turned to Latifa and Aki and imitated Arslan’s words. “...Just be careful on your trip.”

“Yeah.” Aki put on her sharpest expression and imitated Masato, then fistbumped Latifa.

“Ugh...” Masato and Arslan were bright red as they watched.

“I-I don’t know you anymore! Let’s go, Masato!”

“Y-Yeah!” Masato and Arslan retreated from the scene in embarrassment.

“Fufu.” The remaining girls watched their backs and giggled.

Meanwhile, elsewhere in the venue...

“I leave my daughter and her friends to you, Lord Rio.”

Rio, Sara, Orphia, and Alma were talking with the head elders and the relatives of the spirit folk girls. Sara’s father, a silver werewolf man, was entrusting Sara and the others to Rio.

Rio nodded. “Yes. If anything, I’ll be the one in their care...” he said apologetically.

“No, this journey will be a valuable learning experience for our daughters. If you and Lady Aishia act as their guides, we will happily send them away.” Orphia’s father, a high elf man, was speaking cheerfully. However, despite saying that, Rio probably wasn’t imagining the slightly saddened expression on his face.

“Well, as they say: they have to leave the nest at some point. Look after my daughter, Lord Rio!” Alma’s father grabbed Rio’s shoulder heartily. He was younger than Dominic, but his face and body language was very similar to the head elder’s.

While Sara and Orphia’s fathers didn’t look that much older than their daughters, Alma’s father had a face that looked to be around middle-aged for humans. This was a characteristic of the dwarf race, where the males generally had older faces.

“I cannot express my gratitude enough to everyone for entrusting me with their precious daughters. I may rely on them more than they’ll need me, but I vow to protect them to the best of my ability,” Rio pledged respectfully.

At that, Sara and the others blushed in embarrassment.

“Gahaha, that’s like a marriage vow. The girls are getting embarrassed, Rio.” Dominic laughed heartily, slapping Rio on the shoulder.

“Please don’t say such strange things!” Sara and Alma objected to Dominic’s words together.

“Ahaha, well, I’ll be in your care too, Sara, Orphia, Alma,” Rio said, hiding his embarrassment with a wry smile and bowing his head.

“Uh, s-same here, we’ll be counting on you!” Sara’s cheeks reddened, her tail wagging nervously as she bowed her head.

“Thank you, Rio.” Orphia and Alma said. Rio nodded with a faint smile.

“No need to be so formal. From yesterday through today, the girls spent time at their homes and discussed things thoroughly. On top of that, these old men agreed to it and decided to entrust their daughters to you,” Dominic said, patting Rio on the shoulder. “We’re counting on you.”

The fathers all turned their faces away in embarrassment, taking sips of their drinks instead.

“That aside, grandfather. Did you teach Latifa weird words?” Alma sighed in disappointment at Dominic.

“...Hum, whatever could you be talking about?” Dominic cocked his head in wonder.

“Don’t try to play the fool. I’m talking about the local mistress thing!” Alma stated resolutely, refusing to listen to any excuses.

“A-Ahem,” the fathers spat out their drinks, clearing their throats.

“Hey! Old man! What do you think you’re teaching children?!” Alma’s father protested at Dominic in a fluster.

“A-Ah, that? I remember now. I was talking to Latifa about Rio before when my mouth slipped from habit. Well, she probably doesn’t understand it anyway.” Dominic laughed heartily in an attempt to brush off the situation.

“That’s not the problem!” said Alma.

“I-It’s fine, it’s fine. Say, what about you? You’re only a year apart from Latifa. Did you know the meaning?” Dominic said teasingly.

“Uh...!” Alma turned bright red.

“Please don’t tease Alma too much, Dominic,” Rio warned gently as he stood in front of Alma.

“R-Right.” Dominic must have felt some kind of strange pressure from Rio, as he nodded dejectedly.

“I have a little more to say regarding the incident with Latifa. Shall we discuss it over a drink?” Rio sighed tiredly, inviting Dominic to some alcohol.

“Sure, sounds good. All right, you lot come along too! It’s a drinking party for men now!” Dominic called the fathers over in high spirits.

The party continued noisily and late into the night.

◇　◇　◇

The next morning came; it was finally time for Rio to take Miharu and the others back to the Strahl region.

“All right, do you have everything?” Dominic asked, looking at the departing party.

“Yes, I believe so.” Rio looked around at the group and answered on their behalf.

“...Ah!” Vera suddenly remembered something.

“Hm? What’s wrong, Vera?” Ursula asked.

“U-Umm. Latifa, Latifa.” Vera dashed up to her.

“What’s wrong, Vera?” Latifa tilted her head curiously.

“Did you bring the thing?”

“The thing?”

“You know, the thing. The uniforms you made to surprise Rio,” Vera whispered in Latifa’s ear.

“Ooh! That thing. Yup, I brought everyone’s along.” Latifa smiled and nodded in understanding.

“That’s great to hear! You have to surprise Rio, after all.”

“Me...?” Rio must have caught Vera’s words, as he looked on in confusion.

“It’s a secret. You’ll definitely be surprised. I wanted to see it too, but I was told it was a surprise for when you came back, so,” Vera said, grinning.

“I see. I look forward to it, then,” Rio chuckled, looking at Latifa.

“Yup! Aki, Latifa, take care of yourselves. I’ll pray for your safe return,” Vera replied energetically.

“Yeah,” Latifa and Aki nodded. “We’ll be going now!”

“All right, let’s go,” Rio called out to Latifa and Aki.

“Okay!” Latifa said happily, running over to Rio. Meanwhile, Aki approached the giant bird-like spirit, Ariel, waiting next to Orphia.

“Okay everyone, get on Ariel!” Orphia said to Miharu, Aki, Masato, and Sara. The group gathered on Ariel’s back with familiarity, having rode the spirit many times already.

“Yup, there’s enough space for four people there. I’ll carry Alma and Rio will carry Latifa — it’s perfect!” Orphia said in satisfaction once everyone had climbed on Ariel’s back.

“Yup! This is the best option!” Latifa agreed, extremely pleased. She was probably happy that she’d get to stick to Rio through the whole journey.

The only ones who could soar freely through the air among the group were Rio, Orphia, and Ariel. It wasn’t as though Sara and Alma couldn’t fly at all, but their skill was lacking in comparison to Rio and Orphia, so it was faster traveling this way.

That was where the issue of who carried whom came up, and it was decided that the lightest Latifa and Alma would be carried by Rio and Orphia while the remaining members rode on Ariel’s back.

“Don’t move around, okay?” Rio said, picking Latifa up in a princess carry.

“Yup!” Latifa nodded happily.

“...” Alma watched the scene with slight envy.

“You’ll have to put up with me, Alma.” Orphia giggled at Alma.

“There’s nothing to put up with. Thank you for this,” Alma said, climbing onto Orphia’s back.

“Yup,” Orphia replied cheerfully, while Latifa pointed at the sky energetically.

“Okay, let’s go! Full steam ahead!”

“We’ll be going now, everyone!” Rio chuckled, then turned to face everyone who had gathered to see them off. He gently floated into the air, with Orphia and Ariel following close behind.

“Take care!”

“Look after our daughters!”

“Teach me cooking again sometime, Miharu!”

“Let’s play again when you’re back! It’s a promise!”

“Get stronger, Masato!”

Many voices echoed around them.

“Everyone, thank you so much for everything! We’ll definitely come back again! We want to come back again!” Miharu looked down below her and yelled her farewells loudly, which was rare coming from her.

“Later!”

“I want to come back again too!”

Despite having exchanged so many farewells yesterday, Aki and Masato yelled their goodbyes as well.

Afterword

Hello everyone, this is Yuri Kitayama. Thank you for reading Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles, Volume 8: Beyond Memories.

In what feels like the blink of an eye, two years have passed since Seirei Gensouki was serialized, allowing me to release a total of eight volumes so far. This is all thanks to the readers that supported my work and all the people involved in publishing, who I’d like to thank from the bottom of my heart. I am always very grateful to each and every one of you.

Now, since I’m being emotional about the passing of time today, I’d like to look back on the many things that happened in the past two years of this series.

I held an autograph session when Volume 4 went on sale, the manga version of Seirei Gensouki by Tenkla was announced when Volume 5 went on sale, and there was even a popularity poll that was held when Volume 7 went on sale (the results of which are available online), and then the manga was suddenly discontinued...

Ah, and we also ranked on ‘Kono Light Novel ga Sugoi! 2017,’ released last November (thank you very much for that)! And so, with the release of Volume 8, I’d like to use this space to announce something new and exciting.

That being said, the announcement has already been posted everywhere online so I’m sure many of you are aware already, but a new version of the Seirei Gensouki manga will be starting this July. Replacing Tenkla as the artist will be Futago Minaduki, and the new manga series will be composed completely differently to the old one, so please check it out if you haven’t had the chance to yet! (It’s available for free through the website!) Thus ends my manga announcement.

Next, a different topic. Since there are still some lines available in the afterword, I’d like to talk about the main story of the work a little.

How did you find Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles, Volume 8 after the long wait? I believe those who follow the web novel will be largely surprised by the contents.

It was a surprise... right?

Readers of the web novel should have expected things to an extent, like how Miharu did this, or Liselotte did that, or Latifa and the others did this and that. The light novel and web novel have already varied in content quite a bit, but expectations are made to be betrayed.

On the other hand, for the readers who have only read the light novel, I did my best to refine the plot so that the impact of a blank slate could be enjoyed. I hope you were able to enjoy the first time experience only attainable by not reading the web novel.

Thus, whether you’re a web novel reader or light novel reader, there’s no way for an author to discern which is better... but as long as you’ve found Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles, Volume 8 to be interesting, then nothing else could make me happier as an author. I have great plans for Volumes 9 and 10 to be even more exciting in the future, so please keep following this story and give it your love and support.

Finally, to Riv, who once again drew such lovely illustrations: thank you very much! Rikka’s character design really hit a home run with me; I couldn’t stop grinning! Also, congratulations on the birth of your child! I’d like to use this space to offer you my warmest congratulations.

— August 2017, Yuri Kitayama.